Think, then act. When you have learned the techniques, but forget to apply them in
speech, you are acting before thinking. In order to train yourself to think first,
devise a strategy that works for you. For the researcher, it was putting a sheet of
newspaper over the fridge handle. For you, it might be taking a deep breath before
speaking, counting to three, pulling on a rubber band, or even the old school
standby, a string around your finger. The point is, while you are internalizing
these new sounds and rhythms, to create a stopgap measure to get you to focus on the
process and not so much the goal. The four stages of learning. Let's look at the
transition you're going to be going through. One, unconscious incompetence.
You don't even know you're making mistakes. Two, conscious incompetence.
You're aware, but you don't know how to fix them. Three, conscious competence.
When you focus really hard, you're actually pretty good. Four, unconscious
competence. You've internalized the concepts and it's second nature. You're
most likely edging from two to three. To get to four, the key is consistent
practice, a minimum of 15 minutes per day, plus applying the techniques whenever you
talk.